ADEWUMI, TEMIDAYO YINKA

PROFILE

Dedicated, research and result – oriented Public Health Professional with a track record of over 2 years of progressive experience in project and personnel management, child and adolescent health, data gather and reporting, monitoring & evaluation, public relations and organizational development. A highly motivated and enthusiastic individual with proven experience; highly articulated and effective communicator; work well with individuals at all levels; a problem solver and team player, looking forward to give tangible and intangible value to organization & clients/patients towards achieving purpose, while developing self.

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE OFFERED

- Child and Adolescent
 Health
- Project Management
- Public Health Skills
- Work Ethics
- Communication Skills
- Laboratory: Equipment, Processes, Procedures and Techniques •
- Planning and Administration
- Research and Analytical Skills
- Problem Solving
- Data Gathering & Reporting

- Good Time Management
- Microsoft Office Packages
- Statistical Package Such As SPSS, Epi-Data, Epi Info

May 2018 - June 2018

- Interpersonal Skills
- Teamwork

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Academy for Health Development | Graduate Intern Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Proposal writing.
- Manuscript Writing.
- Use of Photo Voice for data collection.
- Use of Epi-Data for data entry.
- Use of Survey CTO for Scripting.
- Qualitative and quantitative research Method.
- Training on Strategic communication.

dfelement

Institute of Advanced Medical Research and Training | Data Entry Officer and Research Assistant Key Responsibilities and Achievements: Oct 2016 - June 2017

- Prepared source data for entry by opening and sorting mail; verifying and logging receipt of data; obtaining missing data.
- Records data by operating data entry equipment; coding information; resolving processing problems.
- Accomplished department and organization mission by completing related results as needed
- Recruit and/or interview subjects.
- Maintained accurate records of interviews, safeguarding the confidentiality of subjects, as necessary.

Sickle Cell Hope Alive Foundation | Project Manager

April 2016 – June 2017

Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Overseen the planning, implementation, and tracking of a specific short-term project which has a beginning, an end and specified deliverables.
- Promoted Foundation and increase awareness.
- Worked independently with founder to generate leads and prospective supporters and funders.
- Identified and developed relationship with potential supports and strategic partners.
- Handled multifaceted clerical tasks (e.g. data entry, filing, records management and billing).
- Ensured the delivery of premium care to the patient and staff, coordinate travel arrangements, maintained database.



- Verification, recording and reporting information.
- Monitored and evaluation of all activities.

NYSC, Oyo State College of Health Science and Technology | Assistant Lecturer Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

June 2015 - April, 2016

- Taught Basic science, microbiology, and chemistry.
- Organized Student's craft exhibition and sales.
- Organized extracurricular activities.

Gender Mobile, Ibadan Chapter | Volunteer

July, 2018 - Till Date

Key Responsibilities and Achievements:

- Organizing campaign and awareness program against gender violence in Ibadan.
- Providing Intervention program among secondary schools in Ibadan.
- Promoting the use of the free toll line for help provided by Gender Mobile for victims.
- Collection, Entry, and Analysis of Data from secondary schools in Ibadan

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

MPH Public Health (Child and Adolescent Health)

2017 - 2019

University of Ibadan, Oyo State

BSc (Hons.) Biochemistry

2010 - 2014

Osun State University, Osun State

Senior School leaving certificate

2006 - 2009

Best Legacy International School, Ogbomoso, Oyo State

CONFERENCE

1st National Conference on Adolescent Health and Development Theme: LEAVING NO YOUNG PERSON BEHIND: ADVANCING ADOLESCENT HEALTH IN NIGERIA IN THE SDG ERA - Organized by Society for Adolescent and Young People's Health in Nigeria, University Of Ibadan, Oyo State

April 10 - 13, 2019

PUBLICATION

E.I.O Ajayi, M.A. Adeleke, T.Y. Adewumi, A.A. Adeyemi (2017) Antiplamodial activities of ethanol extracts of Euporbia hirta whole plant and Vernonia amygdalina leaves in Plasmodium berghei-infected mice, J. Taibah Univ. Sci. (2017) http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jtusci.2017.01.008

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Sex: Female / Date of Birth: 20th January, 1993 / Marital Status: Single

REFERENCES

Available on Request